<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<thing:thing-descriptions bindingId="zwave"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xmlns:thing="https://openhab.org/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0"
  xsi:schemaLocation="https://openhab.org/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0
                      https://openhab.org/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0">

  <thing-type id="ge_58433_00_000" listed="false">
    <label>Enbrighten ZWA4011, 58433 Enbrighten Z-Wave In-Wall Smart Light Switch, 700 Series, 58433</label>
    <description><![CDATA[
Enbrighten Z-Wave In-Wall Smart Light Switch, 700 Series, 58433<br /> <h1>Overview</h1><p>Home automation is even smarter with the Enbrighten Z-Wave In-Wall Smart Switch with QuickFit™ and SimpleWire™. When paired with a compatible hub, the hardwired smart switch operates wall, ceiling and accent lighting through individual commands and programmed settings. Wirelessly control and schedule indoor or outdoor fixtures for effortless management of your home. Your automation possibilities are seemingly infinite when connected to hubs from Ring, Wink, SmartThings, HomeSeer, Vera, American Standard and more.</p><p>About Z-Wave Plus and 700 series with S2 security and SmartStart</p><p>Z-Wave Plus and 700 series further enhance the security and simplicity of previous Z-Wave products. In addition to remaining backward compatible with all Z-Wave generations, 700-series devices feature multiple advancements, including:</p><p>· Over-the-air updates and doubled internal memory.</p><p>· More powerful, robust network capabilities.</p><p>· S2 security with best-in-class secure key exchange to add a layer of 128-bit encryption.</p><p>· SmartStart, which offers unique QR codes for fast, easy pairing.</p><p>· Up to five-year battery life with one coin cell for battery-powered devices.</p> <br /> <h2>Inclusion Information</h2><p>1. Follow the instructions for your Z-Wave certified controller to add a device to the Z-Wave network.</p><p>2. Once the controller is ready to add your device, press the top or bottom of the wireless smart switch (rocker).</p> <br /> <h2>Exclusion Information</h2><p>To remove and reset the device</p><p>1. Follow the instructions for your Z-Wave certified controller to remove a device from the Z-Wave network.</p><p>2. Once the controller is ready to remove your device, press the top or bottom of the wireless smart switch (rocker).</p><p><br /></p> <br /> <h2>Wakeup Information</h2><p><br /></p>
    ]]></description>
    <category>WallSwitch</category>

    <!-- CHANNEL DEFINITIONS -->
    <channels>
      <channel id="switch_binary" typeId="switch_binary">
        <label>Switch</label>
        <properties>
          <property name="binding:*:OnOffType">COMMAND_CLASS_SWITCH_BINARY</property>
        </properties>
      </channel>
      <channel id="scene_number" typeId="scene_number">
        <label>Scene Number</label>
        <properties>
          <property name="binding:*:DecimalType">COMMAND_CLASS_SCENE_ACTIVATION</property>
        </properties>
      </channel>
      <channel id="scene_number" typeId="scene_number">
        <label>Scene Number</label>
        <properties>
          <property name="binding:*:DecimalType">COMMAND_CLASS_CENTRAL_SCENE</property>
        </properties>
      </channel>
    </channels>

    <!-- DEVICE PROPERTY DEFINITIONS -->
    <properties>
      <property name="vendor">Jasco Products</property>
      <property name="modelId">Enbrighten ZWA4011, 58433</property>
      <property name="manufacturerId">0063</property>
      <property name="manufacturerRef">4952:3239</property>
      <property name="dbReference">1669</property>
    </properties>

    <!-- CONFIGURATION DESCRIPTIONS -->
    <config-description>

      <!-- STATIC DEFINITIONS -->
      <parameter name="node_id" type="integer" min="1" max="232" readOnly="true" required="true">
        <label>Node ID</label>
        <advanced>true</advanced>
      </parameter>

    </config-description>

  </thing-type>

</thing:thing-descriptions>
