<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<thing:thing-descriptions bindingId="zwave"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xmlns:thing="https://openhab.org/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0"
  xsi:schemaLocation="https://openhab.org/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0
                      https://openhab.org/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0">

  <thing-type id="sunricher_zv2833pac_00_000" listed="false">
    <label>ZV2833PAC Push-Button Coupler</label>
    <description><![CDATA[
Push-Button Coupler<br /> <h1>Overview</h1><p>This device converts the switches to wireless Z-Wave signal, the coupler can both control other Z-Wave devices and activate scenes in Gateways. The push-button coupler can be included and operated in any Z-Wave network with other Z-Wave certified devices from other manufacturers and/or other applications. All non-battery operated nodes within the network will act as repeaters regardless of vendor to increase reliability of the network.</p><p>Although it is controlling other devices, the device cannot act as Z-Wave network controller (primary or secondary) and will always need a Z-Wave network controller to be included into a Z-Wave network. It also supports the Over The Air (OTA) feature for the product’s firmware upgrade.</p><p>This device supports the SmartStart inclusion. SmartStart enabled products can be added into a Z-Wave network by scanning the Z-Wave QR Code present on the product with a controller providing SmartStart inclusion. No further action is required and the SmartStart product will be added automatically within 10 minutes of being switched on in the network vicinity.</p><p>The push-button coupler has following functions:</p><ol><li>Control of other Z-Wave devices using 'ON', 'OFF', Dim commands.</li><li>Activation of scenes in Gateway mode.</li></ol><p>The encryption modes that the push-button coupler supports are S0, S2 Authenticated, S2 Unauthenticated. When the coupler is being included into a Z-Wave network, you can use your primary controller/gateway to enable one encryption mode or disable encryption. (The primary controller/gateway shall support encryption mode configuration).</p> <br /> <h2>Inclusion Information</h2><p>Step 1. Make sure the push-button coupler does not belong to any Z-Wave network, short press any button, if LED indicator flashes 3 times slowly, the coupler does not belong to any network, then continue step 2, otherwise, it means the coupler has already been included to a network, please first set the coupler to exclusion mode (refer to the part "Exclusion" of this manual),then continue step 2.</p><p>Step 2. Set primary controller/gateway into inclusion mode (Please refer to your primary controllers manual on how to turn your controller into inclusion).</p><p>Step 3. Set the coupler to inclusion mode, there are two methods as follows:</p><ol><li>Triple press the “reset” button, the coupler will be set to inclusion mode, and waiting to be included.</li><li>Power off and power on the coupler, it will be set to inclusion mode, and waiting to be included.</li></ol><p>The coupler is a sleepy device, after inclusion it will not enter into sleepy mode immediately, and will continue activation status for 10s and wait data interaction from the gateway, the LED indicator will flash quickly, please be patient to wait LED indicator to turn off.</p> <br /> <h2>Exclusion Information</h2><p>There are two exclusion methods:</p><p>Method 1: Exclusion from the primary controller/gateway as follows:</p><ol><li>Set the primary controller/gateway into exclusion mode (Please refer to your primary controllers manual on how to set your controller into exclusion).</li><li>Triple press the “reset” button, the coupler will be set to exclusion mode, and waiting to be excluded.</li></ol><p>Method 2: Factory reset the coupler will force it to be excluded from a network. (please refer to the part “Factory Reset” of this manual)</p><p>Note: Factory reset is not recommended for exclusion,</p> <br /> <h2>Wakeup Information</h2><p><br /></p>
    ]]></description>
    <category>WallSwitch</category>

    <!-- CHANNEL DEFINITIONS -->
    <channels>
      <channel id="scene_number" typeId="scene_number">
        <label>Scene Number</label>
        <properties>
          <property name="binding:*:DecimalType">COMMAND_CLASS_CENTRAL_SCENE</property>
        </properties>
      </channel>
    </channels>

    <!-- DEVICE PROPERTY DEFINITIONS -->
    <properties>
      <property name="vendor">Sunricher</property>
      <property name="modelId">ZV2833PAC</property>
      <property name="manufacturerId">0330</property>
      <property name="manufacturerRef">0400:D105</property>
      <property name="dbReference">1477</property>
      <property name="defaultAssociations">1</property>
    </properties>

    <!-- CONFIGURATION DESCRIPTIONS -->
    <config-description>

      <!-- GROUP DEFINITIONS -->
      <parameter-group name="configuration">
        <context>setup</context>
        <label>Configuration Parameters</label>
      </parameter-group>

      <parameter-group name="association">
        <context>link</context>
        <label>Association Groups</label>
      </parameter-group>

      <!-- PARAMETER DEFINITIONS -->
      <parameter name="config_2_1" type="integer" groupName="configuration">
        <label>2: External Switch Type</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
External Switch Type<br /> <h1>Overview</h1><p>0 - Push button</p><p>1 - Normal On/Off switch</p><p>2 - 3-Way switch</p>
        ]]></description>
        <default>0</default>
        <options>
          <option value="0">Push button</option>
          <option value="1">Normal On/Off switch</option>
          <option value="2">3-Way switch</option>
        </options>
      </parameter>

      <parameter name="config_3_1" type="integer" groupName="configuration">
        <label>3: Duration of the Multilevel Start Level Change Up/Down</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
Set the duration of the Multilevel Start Level Change Up/Down<br /> <h1>Overview</h1><p>Set the duration of the Multilevel Start Level Change Up/Down sent when pressing and holding the push button, Valid value: 0-100</p>
        ]]></description>
        <default>8</default>
        <limitToOptions>false</limitToOptions>
      </parameter>

      <parameter name="config_4_1" type="integer" groupName="configuration">
        <label>4: Associations in Z-Wave network Security Mode</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
Associations in Z-Wave network Security Mode<br /> <h1>Overview</h1><p>Enable or disable to set association with association groups in Z-Wave network Security Mode (this parameter is only valid when the coupler is added to an encrypted network):</p><p>0 - disable the setting for all association groups 2, 3, 4&amp;5</p><p>1 - enable the setting for association group 2</p><p>2 - enable the setting for association group 3</p><p>4 - enable the setting for association group 4</p><p>8 - enable the setting for association group 5</p><p>The valid value of this parameter can be a combination, for instance, when set the parameter as 1+2=3, the settings for both association groups 2 and 3 are enabled.</p>
        ]]></description>
        <default>15</default>
        <limitToOptions>false</limitToOptions>
      </parameter>

      <parameter name="config_5_1" type="integer" groupName="configuration">
        <label>5: Scenes sent to the controller for button 1</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
Scenes sent to the controller for button 1<br /> <h1>Overview</h1><p>This parameter defines the actions of push button 1 which can trigger Central Scene (sent to Lifeline group):</p><p>1 - button short pressed once</p><p>2 - button short pressed twice</p><p>4 - button pressed and held</p><p>8 - button released</p><p>The valid value of this parameter can be a combination, for instance, when set the parameter as 1+2=3, the actions of short pressed once and short pressed twice will both work.</p>
        ]]></description>
        <default>15</default>
        <options>
          <option value="1">button short pressed once</option>
          <option value="2">buton short pressed twice</option>
          <option value="4">button pressed and held</option>
          <option value="8">button released</option>
        </options>
        <limitToOptions>false</limitToOptions>
      </parameter>

      <parameter name="config_6_1" type="integer" groupName="configuration">
        <label>6: Scenes sent to the controller for button 2</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
Scenes sent to the controller for button 2<br /> <h1>Overview</h1><p>This parameter defines the actions of push button 2 which can trigger Central Scene (sent to Lifeline group):</p><p>1 - button short pressed once</p><p>2 - button short pressed twice</p><p>4 - button pressed and held</p><p>8 - button released</p><p>The valid value of this parameter can be a combination, for instance, when set the parameter as 1+2=3, the actions of short pressed once and short pressed twice will both work.</p>
        ]]></description>
        <default>15</default>
        <options>
          <option value="1">button short pressed once</option>
          <option value="2">button short pressed twice</option>
          <option value="4">button pressed and held</option>
          <option value="8">button released</option>
        </options>
        <limitToOptions>false</limitToOptions>
      </parameter>

      <parameter name="config_7_1" type="integer" groupName="configuration">
        <label>7: Scenes sent to the controller for button 3</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
Scenes sent to the controller for button 3<br /> <h1>Overview</h1><p>This parameter defines the actions of push button 3 which can trigger Central Scene (sent to Lifeline group):</p><p>1 - button short pressed once</p><p>2 - button short pressed twice</p><p>4 - button pressed and held</p><p>8 - button released</p><p>The valid value of this parameter can be a combination, for instance, when set the parameter as 1+2=3, the actions of short pressed once and short pressed twice will both work.</p>
        ]]></description>
        <default>15</default>
        <options>
          <option value="1">button short pressed once</option>
          <option value="2">button short pressed twice</option>
          <option value="4">button pressed and held</option>
          <option value="8">button released</option>
        </options>
        <limitToOptions>false</limitToOptions>
      </parameter>

      <parameter name="config_8_1" type="integer" groupName="configuration">
        <label>8: Scenes sent to the controller for button 4</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
Scenes sent to the controller for button 4<br /> <h1>Overview</h1><p>This parameter defines the actions of push button 4 which can trigger Central Scene (sent to Lifeline group):</p><p>1 - button short pressed once</p><p>2 - button short pressed twice</p><p>4 - button pressed and held</p><p>8 - button released</p><p>The valid value of this parameter can be a combination, for instance, when set the parameter as 1+2=3, the actions of short pressed once and short pressed twice will both work.</p>
        ]]></description>
        <default>15</default>
        <options>
          <option value="1">button short pressed once</option>
          <option value="2">button short pressed twice</option>
          <option value="4">button pressed and held</option>
        </options>
        <limitToOptions>false</limitToOptions>
      </parameter>

      <parameter name="config_9_1" type="integer" groupName="configuration">
        <label>9: Function of the connected switches</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
Function of the connected switches<br /> <h1>Overview</h1><p>This parameter defines the function of the connected switches:</p><p>0 - function 1</p><p>1 - function 2</p><p>2 - function 3</p>
        ]]></description>
        <default>0</default>
        <options>
          <option value="0">function 1</option>
          <option value="1">function 2</option>
          <option value="2">function 3</option>
        </options>
      </parameter>

      <!-- ASSOCIATION DEFINITIONS -->
      <parameter name="group_1" type="text" groupName="association" multiple="true">
        <label>1: Lifeline</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
<br /> <h1>Overview</h1><p>1. Send Command Class "Device Reset Locally Notification" to associated devices of this group to report factory reset information when factory reset the remote control by pressing and holding down the “reset” button for 10 seconds.</p><p>2. Short press once or twice, press and hold down, release the any of connected switch buttons K1, K2, K3, K4 to send scene activation command to the associated devices of this group using Command Class “Central Scene”. The actions of each switch button that trigger central scene can be configured via parameters 5-8.</p><p>3. When push-button coupler battery power value changes, send Command Class "Battery Report" to associated devices of this group to report power value information.</p>
        ]]></description>
        <multipleLimit>5</multipleLimit>
      </parameter>

      <parameter name="group_2" type="text" groupName="association" multiple="true">
        <label>2: Launch 1</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
<br /> <h1>Overview</h1><h3>Function 1:</h3><p>1. Short press the switch button K1 (or K1+K2 or K1+K2+K3+K4) to send ON/OFF command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Basic Set 0xff/0x00".</p><p>2. Press and hold the switch button K1 (or K1+K2 or K1+K2+K3+K4) to send Dim command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Multilevel Start Level Change Up/Down". (This Command only works when connected switch type is configured as push button, value of configuration parameter 2 configured as 0)</p><h3>Function 2:</h3><p>1. Short press the switch button K1 (or K1+K2) to send ON command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Basic Set 0xff".</p><p>2. Short press the switch button K2 (or K3+K4) to send OFF command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Basic Set 0x00".</p><p>3. Press and hold the switch button K1 (or K1+K2) to send Dim up command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Multilevel Start Level Change Up". (This Command only works when connected switch type is configured as push button, value of configuration parameter 2 configured as 0)</p><p>4. Press and hold the switch button K2 (or K3+K4) to send Dim down command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Multilevel Start Level Change Down". (This Command only works when connected switch type is configured as push button, value of configuration parameter 2 configured as 0)</p><h3>Function 3:</h3><p>1. Short press the switch button K1 to send ON command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Basic Set 0xff".</p><p>2. Short press the switch button K2 to send OFF command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Basic Set 0x00".</p><p>3. Press and hold the switch button K1 to send Dim up command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Multilevel Start Level Change Up". (This Command only works when connected switch type is configured as push button, value of configuration parameter 2 configured as 0)</p><p>4. Press and hold the switch button K2 to send Dim down command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Multilevel Start Level Change Down". (This Command only works when connected switch type is configured as push button, value of configuration parameter 2 configured as 0)</p><p>5. Press and hold the switch button K3 (or K1+K2) to send scene saving command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Scene Actuator Configuration CC",scene ID=0x10. (This Command only works when connected switch type is configured as push button, value of configuration parameter 2 configured as 0)</p><p>6. Press and hold the switch button K4 (or K3+K4) to send scene saving command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Scene Actuator Configuration CC",scene ID=0x20. (This Command only works when connected switch type is configured as push button, value of configuration parameter 2 configured as 0)</p><p>7. Short press the switch button K3 (or K1+K2) to send scene recall command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Scene Activation CC",scene ID=0x10. (This Command only works when connected switch type is configured as push button, value of configuration parameter 2 configured as 0)</p><p>8. Short press the switch button K4 (or K3+K4) to send scene recall command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Scene Activation CC",scene ID=0x20. (This Command only works when connected switch type is configured as push button, value of configuration parameter 2 configured as 0)</p>
        ]]></description>
        <multipleLimit>5</multipleLimit>
      </parameter>

      <parameter name="group_3" type="text" groupName="association" multiple="true">
        <label>3: Launch 2</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
<br /> <h1>Overview</h1><h3>Function 1:</h3><p>1. Short press the switch button K2 (or K3+K4) to send ON/OFF command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Basic Set 0xff/0x00".</p><p>2. Press and hold the switch button K2 (or K3+K4) to send Dim command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Multilevel Start Level Change Up/Down". (This Command only works when connected switch type is configured as push button, value of configuration parameter 2 configured as 0)</p><h3>Function 2:</h3><p>1. Short press the switch button K3 to send ON command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Basic Set 0xff".</p><p>2. Short press the switch button K4 to send OFF command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Basic Set 0x00".</p><p>3. Press and hold the switch button K3 to send Dim up command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Multilevel Start Level Change Up". (This Command only works when connected switch type is configured as push button, value of configuration parameter 2 configured as 0)</p><p>4. Press and hold the switch button K4 to send Dim down command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Multilevel Start Level Change Down". (This Command only works when connected switch type is configured as push button, value of configuration parameter 2 configured as 0)</p>
        ]]></description>
        <multipleLimit>5</multipleLimit>
      </parameter>

      <parameter name="group_4" type="text" groupName="association" multiple="true">
        <label>4: Launch 3</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
<br /> <h1>Overview</h1><p>1. Short press the switch button K3 to send ON/OFF command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Basic Set</p><p>0xff/0x00".</p><p>2. Press and hold the switch button K3 to send Dim command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Multilevel Start Level Change Up/Down". (This Command only works when connected switch type is configured as push button, value of configuration parameter 2 configured as 0)</p>
        ]]></description>
        <multipleLimit>5</multipleLimit>
      </parameter>

      <parameter name="group_5" type="text" groupName="association" multiple="true">
        <label>5: Launch 4</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
<br /> <h1>Overview</h1><p>1. Short press the switch button K4 to send ON/OFF command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Basic Set 0xff/0x00".</p><p>2. Press and hold the switch button K4 to send Dim command to associated devices of this group using Command Class “Multilevel Start Level Change Up/Down". (This Command only works when connected switch type is configured as push button, value of configuration parameter 2 configured as 0)</p>
        ]]></description>
        <multipleLimit>5</multipleLimit>
      </parameter>

      <!-- STATIC DEFINITIONS -->
      <parameter name="node_id" type="integer" min="1" max="232" readOnly="true" required="true">
        <label>Node ID</label>
        <advanced>true</advanced>
      </parameter>

    </config-description>

  </thing-type>

</thing:thing-descriptions>
