<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<thing:thing-descriptions bindingId="zwave"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xmlns:thing="https://openhab.org/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0"
  xsi:schemaLocation="https://openhab.org/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0
                      https://openhab.org/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0">

  <thing-type id="horstmann_ssp301_00_000" listed="false">
    <label>SSP301 Plug-in switch</label>
    <description><![CDATA[
Plug-in switch<br /> <h1>Overview</h1><p>ON/OFF mains power module - unlike the SSP302 this doesn't have energy metering<br /></p> <br /> <h2>Inclusion Information</h2><p>To include the SSP 301 onto a network, put the controller into inclusion mode. Now, press and hold the button on SSP 301 for 4 to 7 seconds then release. The network status LED will start flashing (twice per second) on successful start of inclusion process.</p><p>Note: Refer to the controller's manual for controller relevant actions.</p><p>On successful inclusion the LED will turn off.</p><p>Note: Inclusion means add and exclusion means delete.</p><p>The total process can take up to 20 seconds (Refer to the “Technical specifications – Radio” section for details). If the device fails to join the network it will go back to factory default state and the Network status LED will start flashing once per second. If there is an issue with RF Communication, then re-locate the device and repeat the inclusion process again.</p> <br /> <h2>Exclusion Information</h2><p>To exclude the SSP 301 from a network, put the controller into exclusion mode (refer to controller instructions) and follow the same sequence as per the inclusion process for include node. After successful exclusion the network status LED will start flashing once per second, and the device will reset to factory default.</p><p>If exclusion fails, SSP 301 network status LED will turn off after about 5 seconds.</p><p>Note: Exclusion only works when the device is in direct range of the controller (no repeater allowed).</p> <br /> <h2>Wakeup Information</h2><p><br /></p>
    ]]></description>
    <category>Battery</category>

    <!-- CHANNEL DEFINITIONS -->
    <channels>
      <channel id="switch_binary" typeId="switch_binary">
        <label>Switch</label>
        <properties>
          <property name="binding:*:OnOffType">COMMAND_CLASS_SWITCH_BINARY</property>
        </properties>
      </channel>
    </channels>

    <!-- DEVICE PROPERTY DEFINITIONS -->
    <properties>
      <property name="vendor">Horstmann Controls Limited</property>
      <property name="modelId">SSP301</property>
      <property name="manufacturerId">0059</property>
      <property name="manufacturerRef">000E:0001</property>
      <property name="dbReference">1328</property>
      <property name="defaultAssociations">1</property>
    </properties>

    <!-- CONFIGURATION DESCRIPTIONS -->
    <config-description>

      <!-- GROUP DEFINITIONS -->
      <parameter-group name="association">
        <context>link</context>
        <label>Association Groups</label>
      </parameter-group>

      <!-- ASSOCIATION DEFINITIONS -->
      <parameter name="group_1" type="text" groupName="association" multiple="true">
        <label>1: Lifeline</label>
        <description>Lifeline</description>
        <multipleLimit>1</multipleLimit>
      </parameter>

      <!-- STATIC DEFINITIONS -->
      <parameter name="node_id" type="integer" min="1" max="232" readOnly="true" required="true">
        <label>Node ID</label>
        <advanced>true</advanced>
      </parameter>

    </config-description>

  </thing-type>

</thing:thing-descriptions>
