<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<thing:thing-descriptions bindingId="zwave"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:thing="http://eclipse.org/smarthome/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://eclipse.org/smarthome/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0 org.eclipse.smarthome.thing-description.xsd">

	<thing-type id="device" listed="false">
		<label>Unknown Device</label>
		<description><![CDATA[
		  This device has not been fully discovered by the binding. There are a few possible reasons for this -:
		  <ul>
		  <li><b>The device is not in the database.</b> If the device attributes show that this device has a valid
		  manufacturer ID, device ID and type, then this is likely the case (eg. you see a label like "<i>Z-Wave node 1
		  (0082:6015:020D::2.0)</i>"). Even if the device appears to be in the database, some manufacturers use multiple
		  sets of references for different regions or versions, and your device references may not be in the database.
		  In either case, the database must be updated and you should raise an issue to get this addressed.
		  <li><b>The device initialisation is not complete.</b> Once the device is included into the network, the binding
		  must interrogate it to find out what type of device it is. One part of this process is to get the manufacturer
		  information required to identify the device, and until this is done, the device will remain unknown. For mains
		  powered devices, this will occur quickly, however for battery devices the device must be woken up a number of
		  times to allow the discovery phase to complete. This must be performed with the device close to the controller.  
		  </ul> 
		]]></description>

        <!-- CONFIGURATION DESCRIPTIONS -->
        <config-description>

            <!-- PARAMETER DEFINITIONS -->
            <parameter name="node_id" type="integer" min="1" max="232" readOnly="true" required="true">
                <label>Node ID</label>
            </parameter>
        </config-description>

	</thing-type>

</thing:thing-descriptions>
