<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<thing:thing-descriptions bindingId="zwave"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xmlns:thing="https://openhab.org/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0"
  xsi:schemaLocation="https://openhab.org/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0
                      https://openhab.org/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0">

  <thing-type id="everspring_an180_00_000" listed="false">
    <label>AN180 Switch without metering</label>
    <description><![CDATA[
Switch without metering<br /><h1>Overview</h1><p>The On/Off Mini Plug is a Z-Wave enabled device which is fully compatible with any Z-Wave enabled network. Z-WaveTM enabled devices displaying the Z-Wave logo can also be used with it regardless of the manufacturer, and ours can also be used in other manufacturer’s Z-Wave enabled networks. Inclusion of this unit on other manufacturer’s Wireless Controller menu allows remote operation of the unit and the connected load. The On/Off Mini Plug is designed to control the on/off status of appliances load in your house. At 220-240V voltage, this Plug can support up to 1500W resistive.</p> <br /><h2>Inclusion Information</h2><h4>Adding to Z-Wave Network</h4> <p>On the unit you can find a link key which is used to carry out the function of inclusion, exclusion, and reset. When power is applied for the first time, the LED will flash on and off alternately and repeatedly, implying that it has not been assigned a node ID and cannot work with other Z-Wave devices yet. This unit supports the Auto Inclusion function when power is applied and no node ID is stored in the memory.</p> <h4>Auto Inclusion</h4> <p>The module may automatically execute the function of inclusion when...</p> <ol><li>The power is applied for the first time and no node ID has been stored in the module.</li> <li>The execution of reset is successful where the stored node ID is cleared.</li> </ol><p><strong>Note</strong>: The duration for Auto Inclusion is about 4 minutes. Unlike the “inclusion” procedure shown in the table below, the execution of Auto Inclusion is automatic without the necessity of pressing the link key.</p> <h4>Inclusion</h4> <ol><li>Put the Z-Wave Controller into inclusion mode.</li> <li>Press the link key three times within 1.5 seconds to put the unit into inclusion mode.</li> </ol><h4>No node ID</h4> <p>The Controller does not allocate a node ID to the unit. -&gt; LED indication: 2-second on, 2-second off</p> <h4>Reset</h4> <p>(Use this procedure only in the event that the network primary controller is missing, or otherwise inoperable.)</p> <ol><li>Press the link key three times within 1.5 seconds to put the unit into exclusion mode.</li> <li>Within 1 secondof step 1, press link key again and hold it until LED is off (about 5 seconds).</li> <li>Node ID is excluded.The device reverts to factory default state and will be in auto-inclusion mode for 4 minutes.</li> </ol><br /><h2>Exclusion Information</h2><ol><li>Put the Z-Wave Controller into exclusion mode.</li> <li>Press the link key three times within 1.5 seconds to put the unit into exclusion mode.</li> </ol>
    ]]></description>
    <category>PowerOutlet</category>

    <!-- CHANNEL DEFINITIONS -->
    <channels>
      <channel id="switch_binary" typeId="switch_binary">
        <label>Switch</label>
        <properties>
          <property name="binding:*:OnOffType">COMMAND_CLASS_SWITCH_BINARY,COMMAND_CLASS_BASIC</property>
        </properties>
      </channel>
      <channel id="alarm_general" typeId="alarm_general">
        <label>Alarm (general)</label>
        <properties>
          <property name="binding:*:OnOffType">COMMAND_CLASS_ALARM;type=GENERAL</property>
        </properties>
      </channel>
      <channel id="alarm_power" typeId="alarm_power">
        <label>Alarm (power)</label>
        <properties>
          <property name="binding:*:OnOffType">COMMAND_CLASS_ALARM;type=POWER_MANAGEMENT</property>
        </properties>
      </channel>
    </channels>

    <!-- DEVICE PROPERTY DEFINITIONS -->
    <properties>
      <property name="vendor">Everspring</property>
      <property name="modelId">AN180</property>
      <property name="manufacturerId">0060</property>
      <property name="manufacturerRef">0004:0007</property>
      <property name="dbReference">481</property>
      <property name="defaultAssociations">1</property>
    </properties>

    <!-- CONFIGURATION DESCRIPTIONS -->
    <config-description>

      <!-- GROUP DEFINITIONS -->
      <parameter-group name="configuration">
        <context>setup</context>
        <label>Configuration Parameters</label>
      </parameter-group>

      <parameter-group name="association">
        <context>link</context>
        <label>Association Groups</label>
      </parameter-group>

      <!-- PARAMETER DEFINITIONS -->
      <parameter name="config_1_2" type="integer" groupName="configuration"
                 min="0" max="99">
        <label>1: Basic Set Command value</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
Defines value for Basic Set command<br /><h1>Overview</h1><p>Range: 0~99 , 255</p>
        ]]></description>
        <default>255</default>
        <options>
          <option value="255">On</option>
        </options>
        <limitToOptions>false</limitToOptions>
      </parameter>

      <parameter name="config_2_1" type="integer" groupName="configuration"
                 min="3" max="25">
        <label>2: Delaying time Group 1</label>
        <description>The delaying time to report to Group 1</description>
        <default>3</default>
      </parameter>

      <parameter name="config_3_1" type="integer" groupName="configuration"
                 min="0" max="1">
        <label>3: Remember the last status</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
Remember the last status<br /><h1>Overview</h1><p>0: do not remember1: remember </p>
        ]]></description>
        <default>1</default>
      </parameter>

      <!-- ASSOCIATION DEFINITIONS -->
      <parameter name="group_1" type="text" groupName="association">
        <label>1: Lifeline</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
Controller communicaion<br /><h1>Overview</h1><p>Supports: Binary Switch Report, Notification Report, Device Reset Locally Notification</p> <ul><li>When the unit is powered for the first time, the unit will send a Notification Report to the node of Group 1. </li> <li>When setting the unit or changing the unit’s status, the unit will send a Binary Switch Report to the node of Group 1. </li> <li>Device Reset: When performing Reset the unit will send Device Reset Locally Notification to the node of Group1. </li> <li>The minimum interval time between two reports sent from this unit to the node of Group 1 is 3 seconds. Refer to Configuration parameter 2 for more information.</li> </ul>
        ]]></description>
      </parameter>

      <parameter name="group_2" type="text" groupName="association" multiple="true">
        <label>2: On/Off control</label>
        <description><![CDATA[
On/Off control<br /><h1>Overview</h1><p>When the <strong>button</strong> on the unit or the wall switch is pressed, the unit will send a <strong>Basic Set</strong> command to the nodes of Group 2. When the unit is OFF, Basic Set Value = 0x00. When the unit is ON, Basic Set Value = 0xFF (255). </p>
        ]]></description>
        <multipleLimit>4</multipleLimit>
      </parameter>

      <!-- STATIC DEFINITIONS -->
      <parameter name="node_id" type="integer" min="1" max="232" readOnly="true" required="true">
        <label>Node ID</label>
        <advanced>true</advanced>
      </parameter>

    </config-description>

  </thing-type>

</thing:thing-descriptions>
